Guide to the Park City Mountain Resort audio-visual collection 1961-2002
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
- Television news coverage, 1992 September 22-1993 April 25; VHS videocassette (Cassette 155)
  11/07 KSL 9 am "Park City opened Friday"
  11/06 KBYU 6:30 pm "Park City opens"
  11/17 KUTV 5 pm "Sterling learns to ski at Park City"
  11/18 KUTV 5 pm "Sterling learns to ski at Park City"
  11/19 KUTV 5 pm "Sterling learns to ski at Park City"
  11/23 KUTV 5 pm "Sterling learns to ski at Park City"
  11/23 KSTU 9 pm "Record snowfall"
  11/24 KTVX 5:30 pm "World Cup skiing: Terzian"
  11/27 KUTV 5 pm "Weather from Park City"
  11/27 KUTV 6 pm "Ski technicians / snow quality"
  11/27 KUTV 6 pm "World Cup skiing"
  11/27 KUTV 10 pm "World Cup skiing / celebration"
  11/27 KUTV 10 pm "World Cup skiing"
  11/27 KTVX 5:30 pm "World Cup skiing"
  11/28 KSL 10 pm "World Cup skiing"
  11/28 KUTV 9 am "World Cup skiing"
  11/28 KUTV 6 pm "World Cup skiing"
  11/28 KTVX 5 pm "World Cup skiing"
  11/29 KSL 5:30 pm "World Cup skiing"
  11/29 KUTV 8:30 am "World Cup skiing"
  11/29 KUTV 5:30 pm "Park City retailers / great skiing"
  11/29 KUTV 5:30 pm "World Cup skiing"
  11/29 KTVX 5:30 pm "World Cup skiing"
  12/01 KTVX 5:30 pm "Good ski deals"
  12/05 KUTV 6 pm "Julie Parisien is World Cup winner"
  KTVX Images "Behind the scenes at World Cup"
  12/11 KUTV 10 pm "Pioneer ski instructors visit"
  KTVX 5:30 pm "Pro Racing"
  12/12 KSL 10 pm "Pro Racing"
  KUTV 10 pm "Pro Racing"
  KTVX 5 pm "Pro Racing"
  KTVX 10 pm "Employee killed"
  12/13 KSL 10 pm "Employee killed"
  KUTV 8:30 am "Pro Racing"
  KUTV 5:30 pm "Pro Racing"
  KSTU 10 pm "Employee killed"
  12/14 KUTV Noon "Employee killed"
  12/19 KTVX 5 pm "Winter Games activities"
  KTVX 10 pm "Winter Games activities"
  12/25 KTVX 5:30 pm "Mr. and Mrs. Claus go skiing"
  1/9/93 KTVX 5:30 pm "FIS Women's Slalom"
  1/16 KSL 9 am "Senator's Ski Cup"
  1/16 KSL 6 pm "Senator's Ski Cup"
  1/22 KTVX 5:30 pm "Huntsman Cup Ski Race"
  1/23 KTVX 5:30 pm "Skiing deals / discounts"
  1/24 KTVX 5:30 pm "Huntsman Cup Ski Race"
  2/01 KSL 8 am "USWest / Boys & Girls Club ski"
  2/03 KUTV 12 pm "USWest / Boys & Girls Club ski"
  2/05 KUTV 6 pm "Weather/Park City Ski Resort"
  2/06 KUTV 9 am "Mademoiselle on the mountain"
  2/20 KUTV 12:30 pm "Inside Stuff: Lou Hudson ski instructor"
  2/20 KTVX 5:30 pm "Park City handicap ski race"
  2/20 KTVX 10 pm "US Alpine races"
  2/20 KTVX 10 pm "Jans slalom handicapped ski race"
  2/26 KTVX 5:30 pm "Ski season extended"
  4/14 KTVX 5:30 pm "Ski season extended"
  4/17 KTVX 5:30 pm "Historical tours / Al's Hill"
  4/22 KTVX 10 pm "Ski magazine at Park City Ski Resort"
  4/25 KSL 5:30 pm "Park City Ski Resort closes"
- KTVX new stories - Park City Ski Area ski season, 1992-1993; VHS videocassette (Cassette 156)
  This video is a compilation of all of KTVX's news reports that have any correlation to Park City Ski Area. These reports contain information on Park City Ski Area's opening dates, what goes into hosting a World Cup event and the differences between the World Cup circuit and the Pro Cup circuit, fundraisers and races for disabled skiers, and the instillation of chair lifts at Park City Ski Area.
- U.S. Pro Cup Ski Tour: men's giant slalom, 1993 January 01; VHS videocassette (Cassette 157)
  This video contains ESPN's coverage of the 1992/1993 U.S. Pro Cup ski race. It shows highlights from the round of thirty-two and a full live coverage of the round of sixteen, the quarterfinals, semifinals, and the finals. Throughout the race ESPN plays clips from past Pro Cup races that mainly feature Bernard Knauss. After the race the announcers interview Ove Nygren who took first place.
- Utah Fest, 1993 January 21; VHS videocassette (Cassette 158)
  >Utah Fest is a television program on the Weather Channel that features Utah's winter weather. In this episode, the forecaster explains what makes Utah's snow the greatest snow on earth. Then he gives the local weather forecast for Park City and Salt Lake City followed by the extended forecast. Lastly he reviews the ski conditions and shows satellite pictures of the West Coast and discusses the potential snowfall.
- NBC Inside Stuff: Park City ski instructor, 1993 February 20; VHS videocassette (Cassette 159)
  This video contains a news report on a ski instructor at Park City Ski Area named Lou Hudson who is a former NBA (National Basketball Association) All Star basketball player. The news reporter interviews Lou on the chairlift at Park City Ski Area. In this interview, Lou discusses his experiences as a ski instructor and his new program for teaching local Park City children how to play basketball.
- America's Opening World Cup footage, 1993 October 27; VHS videocassette (Cassette 160)
  This video contains footage from the 1993 World Cup men's giant slalom and slalom events. Most of the footage is shot from the starting gate and the middle of the course.
- America's Opening World Cup advertisement, 1993 October 27; U-matic videocassette, VHS videocassette, Betacam videocassette (Cassette 161)
  This video contains a thirty-second advertisement for the America's Opening World Cup event held at Park City Ski Area over the Thanksgiving weekend of 1993. It highlights times, dates, event schedule information and ticket information.
  5 cassettes
- Park City ski story, 1993 November 19; VHS videocassette (Cassette 162)
  This video contains a news report on the concern that Utah ski areas had due to the lack of snow in the early ski season of 1993. They report that a recent snowfall helps attract local skiers but that the tourists are not likely to spend their thanksgiving ski vacation in Utah. The report is followed by Utah's extended forecast.
- America's Opening World Cup event video, 1993 October; U-matic videocassette (Cassette 163)
  This is a promotional video for the America's Opening 1993 World Cup event. It shows what it takes to become a member of the U.S. Ski Team along with the top racers' accomplishments.
- Television news coverage, 1993 December 03-29; VHS videocassette (Cassette 164)
  12/03 KSTU 9 pm "Drug testing at Ski Resorts"
  12/10 KUTV 6 pm "Elder hostel"
  12/11 KSL 10 pm "Live with Mark Menlove on ski industry"
  12/12 KSL 5:30 pm "Big snowfall helps resorts"
  12/24 KSL 6 pm "Resorts report big bookings"
  12/26 KTVX 5:30 pm "Skimpy snow but big bookings"
  12/29 KSTU 9 pm"Ski magazine and snow country ratings"
  12/29 KSTU 9 pm "Ski magazine and snow country ratings"
- Television news coverage, 1993 August 26-November 30; VHS videocassette (Cassette 165)
  The August news coverage in this video contains a report on the instillation of the King Kong chairlift at Park City Ski Area.
  The October news coverage contains information on Park City Ski Area's new policy of random drug testing for the employees, Olympic construction to raise the bid for Utah being the Olympic venue for the 2002 Winter Olympics, and on Salt Lake City being ranked one of the top ten places to live.
  The November news coverage contains information on Park City Ski Area's opening dates, Park City's preparation for the America's Opening World Cup event, holiday bookings at Utah ski resorts, tips for physically preparing for the ski season, and on the first installment of $30,000,000 out of $75,000,000 given to the Salt Lake City Olympic bid committee by Park City Ski Area to help increase the chances of having the 2002 Winter Olympics in Utah.
- KTVX new stories - Park City Ski Area ski season, 1993-1994; VHS videocassette (Cassette 166)
  This video is a compilation of all of KTVX's news reports that have any correlation to Park City Ski Area. These reports contain information on the instillation of chair lifts, the importance of preparing your body for the ski season and how to do so, Holly Flanders' ski clinic for women, and the sponsored junior racing program at Park City Ski Area that offers underprivileged kids an experience that they would not have otherwise had.
- Television news coverage, 1994 January 06-22; VHS videocasette (Cassette 167)
  1/06 KUTV 5 pm "Weather: skiing at Park City"
  1/06 KSTU 9 pm "Weather: skiing at Park City"
  1/07 KSTU 9 pm "Disabled skiers at Park City"
  1/09 KSL 10 pm "Road to Gold: Erik Schlopy"
  1/11 KSL 6 pm "Road to Gold: Kristi Terzian"
  1/14 KTVX 6 am "Live phone interview: Gay and lesbian ski week"
  1/14 KSTU 9 pm "U.S. Senators ski Cup"
  1/16 KSL 5:30 pm "Road to Gold: Jeremy Nobis"
  1/16 KUTV 10 pm "Gay winter fest ski week"
  1/20 KSL 7 pm "Road to Gold: Utah Olympic athletes (1/2 hour)"
  1/20 KSL 7:30 pm "Winter fest: preparations for Olympics"
  1/21 KSL 6 pm "Handicapped ski races"
  1/22 KSTU 9 pm "Huntsman Cup Trials"
- Television news coverage, 1994 February 05-26; VHS videocassette (Cassette 168)
  2/5 KTVX Images (3 stories)
  2/6 KSL 10 pm "Skiers qualify for Olympics"
  2/7 KSL Noon "Skiers head for Olympics"
  2/8 KSL Noon "Send off party"
  2/10 KTVX Inside Edition "Senators Cup"
  2/12 KSTU 9 pm "Utahans are optimistic for Olympics"
  KSTU 9 pm "Skiers head for Park City"
  2/13 KTVX 10 pm "Tommy Moe wins"
  2/14 KSL Noon "Experts head to Norway to learn"
  2/18 KSL 6 pm "U.S. Ski Team celebrates"
  2/21 KSTU 9 pm "Presidents day weekend"
  2/22 KTVX 10 pm "Olympic update"
  2/23 KSL 6:30 pm "Jeremy Nobis Road to Gold"
  KTVX 5:30 pm "Jeremy Nobis in Giant Slalom"
  2/26 KSL 10 pm "Jeremy Nobis Olympic update"
- Television news coverage, 1994 March 12-31; VHS videocassette (Cassette 169)
  3/12 KTVX 5 pm "Jans Rossignol Challenge"
  3/13 KSL 5:30 pm "Winter sports in Utah"
  3/18 KTVX 5:30 pm "Women's ski lessons"
  3/30 KTVX 5:30 pm "Spring Skiing"
  3/31 KTVX 5:30 pm "Park West sold - Park City rumors"
  3/31 KSTU 9 pm "Spring Skiing"
- Television news coverage, 1994 April 02-14; VHS videocassette (Cassette 170)
  4/02 KUTV 9 am "Easter egg hunt"
  4/04 KSL 6 pm "Park City Ski Resort sold to Powder Corp."
  4/04 KTVX 5:30 pm "Park City Ski Area sold to Ian Cummings"
  4/04 KTVX 10 pm "Park City Ski Area sold to Ian Cummings"
  4/14 KTVX 6 am "Candy Erickson on 1993-1994 season"
- Lobbyist gifts, Senators Ski Cup, 1994 May 11; VHS videocassette (Cassette 171)
  This video contains a news report on the cancellation of the Senators Ski Cup. The Senators Ski Cup was canceled because it was believed to have been a way for lobbyists to win over the popular vote of the senate on various political issues. Along with the cancellation of the Senators Ski Cup, restrictions were placed on what the senators could and could not accept. The restrictions include the termination of free trips and lunches, and the senators are no longer able to accept gifts from anyone but family and close friends.
- Park City Ski Area local commercial, 1994 September 07; U-matic videocassette, Betacam videocassette (Cassette 172)
  This thirty-second commercial advertises Park City Ski Area as Utah's largest ski area where you can always find the terrain you are looking for. It also advertises discounted pass rates provided that they are purchased early in the season.
- America's Opening World Cup advertisement, 1994 October 26; U-matic videocassette, Betacam videocassette, VHS videocassette (Cassette 173)
  This video contains a thirty-second advertisement for the America's Opening World Cup event hosted at Park City Ski Area over Thanksgiving weekend of 1994. It highlights times, dates, event schedule information, and ticket information.
  6 cassettes
- America's Opening World Cup advertisement, 1994 November 10; 1-inch videotape (Reel 174)
- Reel Thrills: The Après Ski Show, 1994 December 27; VHS videocassette (Cassette 175)
  Reel Thrills is a program aired on the Resort Sports Network. It features clips from various sports films and interviews with the filmmakers. In this episode the featured sports are skiing and snowboarding.
  The films shown are: "2 Board With The World" by Joe Jay Jalbert, "The Hedonist" by Steve Winter and Murray Wais, "Ptex, Lies, and Duct Tape" by Greg Stumps, "Extremely Peppered" by Blake Miller, "It's The Source" by Jon Long and James Angrove, "Las Lenas '94" by Mike Ferrari and Alejandro Vayo, and "Crunch" by Sandy Santucci.
- Snow slippers, 1994; VHS videocassette (Cassette 176)
  This video contains a five-minute advertisement for Cliff Taylor's Magic Motion System and for the Cliff Taylor Ski Center. The Magic Motion System is based on Cliff Taylor's invention, Snow slippers. Snow slippers aid in the process of learning to turn on skis.
- Avalanche on KPCW news with Chris Eisenberg, 1995 January 03; Audiocassette (Cassette 177)
  This is an avalanche control news report by Chris Eisenberg on KPCW news. Chris Eisenberg tags along with the Park City avalanche ski patrol in order to give a detailed and accurate report.
- Spinal Snap teaser, 1995 February 07; VHS videocassette (Cassette 178)
  This is an extreme skiing video produced by Rob Bruce Films. It contains footage of various extreme skiers and snowboarders each skiing through moguls, powder, off cliffs down chutes and more.
- Full Access on tour with Pam Tillis, 1995 February 09; VHS videocassette (Cassette 179)
  This video contains an interview with country singer Pam Tillis who was awarded the number one female vocalist of the year at the Country Music Awards (CMA). Throughout the interview, there are clips of her Salt Lake City concert at Capital Theatre, the CMA Awards Ceremony, and of Pam skiing at Park City Ski Area.
- Park City Ski Area demo tape: Steve Carlson, 1995 August 18; Audiocassette (Cassette 180)
  This item cannot be heard due to demagnification of the tape.
- KUED project funding, 1995 October 17; VHS videocassette (Cassette 181)
  This video contains a thirty-second advertisement aired after KUED programs that lists companies who fund KUED programming. These companies include Park City Ski Area, Granite Furniture Company and O.C Tanner Jewelry.
- Teck Talk: Peter Keelty and Holly Flanders, 1995 November 16; VHS videocassette (Cassette 182)
  Teck Talk is a show that was designed to educate people on how to find the appropriate ski equipment for their style and level of skiing. Peter Keelty and Holly Flanders are the hosts of this show and they feature five of the top skis in the following categories: giant slalom, "easy carvers" or shape skis, slalom, "groomer cruisers", all mountain and extreme or three-dimensional skis.
- Park City opens - Fox News, 1995 November 28; VHS videocassette (Cassette 183)
  This video contains a report on ski areas that are making an effort to lower ticket prices for residential families through special packages and discount coupons. It also contains a report on the opening dates for Park City Ski Area and a local weather forecast.
- Subaru Ski World with Bob Beattie: Utah Ski Areas, 1995 December 03; VHS videocassette (Cassette 184)
  Subaru Ski World is an ESPN program hosted by Bob Beattie. In this episode of Ski World, Bob Beattie explains why Utah has the lightest and driest snow. He showcases several ski areas in Utah including Alta and Snowbird for the best powder and Deer Valley for being the most luxurious. Bob also hosts interviews with Stein Erikson, Tommy Moe, and Kristi Terzian.
- See For Yourself: Winter in Park City, Utah, 1995; VHS videocassette (Cassette 185)
  This video contains an advertisement for Park City, Utah. "See for yourself. Discover why Park City is host to many venues for the 2002 Olympic Winter Games. It's three resorts in one great town. It's Deer Valley Resort, Park City Ski Area, and Wolf Mountain. It's the great snow conditions and abundant terrain (4700 skiable acres at the three resorts all within a five mile radius). You can even try jumping at the Utah Winter Sports Park - from the beginning ski play area to flying off the K-18 or K-38 meter jumps. Or if you prefer, you can watch the seasoned Nordic skiers soar off the 65 or 90 meter Olympic jump. Besides skiing, there is plenty to keep you busy. This historic mining town has more shopping, dining and nightlife than you have time for. And what's really worth seeing is how easy it is to get here just 40 minutes from Salt Lake City International Airport."
- Park City spring break, 1996 February 29; Audiocassette (Cassette 186)
  This is an R&R Advertisement aired on Park City Radio. The advertisement is sixty-seconds long and advertises special airfare rates if flying into Salt Lake City for a spring break ski vacation at Park City Ski Area.
- All Things Considered, 1996 April 24; Audiocassette (Cassette 187)
  All Things Considered is a radio program in which many issues are discussed. In this particular program they discuss Park City Ski Area's decision to open the mountain to snowboarders. Charlie Lansche and Robbie Beck, both employees of Park City Ski Area, discuss this matter with the program hosts and respond to phone calls from the public.
- Television news coverage, 1996 April 18-30; VHS videocassette (Cassette 188)
  4/18/96 KUTV 12 PM "New Lift" This is a report on a six person, high-speed chair lift installed at Park City Ski Area. The new lift replaced the prospector lift.
  4/23/96 KTVX 5:30 PM "Snowboarding"
  4/24/96 KTVX 5:30 AM "Snowboarding" This is a report on Park City Ski Area's decision to open the Mountain to snowboarders.
  4/30/96 KUTV 10 PM "New Lifts" This is a report on a recall of several new chair lifts due to safety regulations.
- Park City Ski Area pass rates, 1996 September 09; Audiocassette (Cassette 189)
  This tape contains two sixty-second advertisements. The first advertises a savings of over $300 on Park City Ski Area season passes. The second advertises a savings of over $180 on Park City Ski Area season passes.
- America's Opening World Cup advertisement, 1996 October 30; VHS videocassette, U-matic videocassette (Cassette 190)
  This is a thirty-second advertisement for the America's Opening World Cup event held at Park City Ski Area over the Thanksgiving weekend of 1996. It highlights times, dates, event schedule information and ticket information.
- Chevy Truck Skiing Magazine on television, 1996 November; VHS videocassette (Cassette 191)
  This video contains clips from the 1996 World Cup flag parade, street dance, and the Men's World Cup Slalom event.
- Skier's Forecast, 1996 December 06; VHS videocassette (Cassette 192)
  Skier's Forecast is a program that is aired on the weather channel. It contains a local weather forecast, ski conditions and resort reports.
- Ski World with Bob Beattie, 1996 December 08; VHS videocassette (Cassette 193)
  Ski World is an ESPN program hosted by Bob Beattie. In this episode Bob Beattie hosts various interviews at Park City Ski Area. Interviewees include Dave Downing and Shannon Dunn who are two of the top snowboarders, Kristi Terzian who raced on the U.S. Ski Team, Kristen Ulmer who ranks number one for female extreme skiing, and Tommy Moe and Shannon Nobis who both ski for the U.S. Ski Team.
- Park City Ski Area's official Blazer, 1996 December 09; VHS videocassette (Cassette 194)
  This video contains a thirty-second advertisement for Chevrolet/Geo becoming Park City Ski Area's official Blazer.
- Snowboarding industry conference and "Powder Quest", 1996; VHS videocassette (Cassette 195)
  This is a video invitation to the Trans-world seventh annual snowboarding conference in Vail, Colorado. The video is formatted after the James Bond movie GoldenEye (Martin Campbell 1995). The mission, "Red Eye," is to pick up and hand off a red backpack. The backpack contains a video that reveals the next mission which is to attend the snowboarding conference in Vail.
- RSN.com resort-cam, circa 1996-1997; VHS videocassette (Cassette 196)
  This video contains an advertisement for the Resort Sports Network's new website. The website provides various ski resorts information.
- Utah ski industry, 1997 February 23; VHS videocassette (Cassette 197)
  This video contains an interview with Deer Valley's director of skiing and Olympic gold medallist, Stein Eriksen, Snowbird's director of skiing, Junior Bonous, and the President of the Park City Ski Corporation, Phil Jones. In this interview they discuss why skiing is the greatest sport on Earth, the evolution of ski equipment, changes in Utah skiing, and the pros and cons of having the Winter Olympics in Utah.
- Side cut skis, senior ski club, 1997 February 24; VHS videocassette (Cassette 198)
  This video contains a news report on side cut skis and on a senior citizen ski club. The report on the side cut skis includes the scientific design of parabolic skis and Information on why ski resorts invested so much into the designing of these skis. The report on the senior citizens ski club includes interviews with the club members and footage from their race at Park City Ski Area.
- Ski Utah volume one, 1996 November 09-30; VHS videocassette (Cassette 199)
  Ski Utah is a television program that was aired every Saturday November 9-March 8. Each episode follows a basic pattern: the hosts spotlight various Utah Ski resorts and give skiing or snowboarding tips.
  "Ski Shape" tips are tips for preparing for the ski season, staying in shape for the season and exercising to prevent injury.
  "The Cutting Edge" is a brief introduction to new gear.
  "Ski Stat" is a report on ski resort statistics.
  "Ski Slate" is a calendar of events for ski resorts.
  "Steep Thrills" is an introduction to extreme runs at local Utah ski resorts.
- Ski Utah volume two, 1996 December 07-1997 January 04; VHS videocassette (Cassette 200)
  See the description for cassette 199 for an outline of the Ski Utah program.
- Ski Utah volume three, 1997 January 11-February 08; VHS videocassette (Cassette 201)
- Ski Utah volume four, 1997 February 15-March 08; VHS videocassette (Cassette 202)
- Sniagrab - Denver version, 1997 August 19; VHS videocassette (Cassette 203)
  This video contains twelve fifteen-second advertisements for a sale at Gart Sports. Each advertisement highlights a different item that is on sale and gives sale dates, times and locations.
- Utah business show, 1997 August 19; VHS videocassette (Cassette 204)
  This video contains a report on Ski Resorts that are no longer famous for just skiing. They report on Sundance which is famous for it's summer mountain biking, hiking, horseback riding, and arts programs as well as Park City Ski Area which, in the spirit of evolving into a summer destination as well as a winter destination, has changed it's name to Park City Mountain Resort. Park City Mountain Resort is famous for its summer alpine slide, miniature golf, hiking, shopping and much more.
- Park City "EZ Access", 1997 September 16; Audiocassette (Cassette 205)
  This tape contains a sixty-second advertisement for Park City Mountain Resort's new six person, high-speed chair lift, the new snowboard park, and the easy access pass that gets you straight onto the lift without waiting in any ticket lines.
- Snowriders 2 trailer - Salt Lake City version, 1997 October; VHS videocassette (Cassette 206)
  This video contains a five-minute advertisement for a Warren Miller production called Snowriders 2.
- America's Opening World Cup advertisement, 1997 November 13; VHS videocassette, Betacam videocassette (Cassette 207)
  This video contains a thirty-second advertisement and a ten-second revised advertisement for the America's Opening World Cup event hosted by Park City Mountain Resort over thanksgiving weekend of 1997. The add highlights times, dates, event schedule information and ticket information with clips from World Cup races in the background.
- America's Opening World Cup - KTVX coverage, 1997 November; VHS videocassette (Cassette 208)